Come in.
ادخل.
(Episode 75)
(الحلقة 75)
Let go! Let go of me, you punks! Do you have any idea who I am?!
دعوني! دعوني أيها الأوغاد! هل لديكم أدنى فكرة عن هويتي؟!
What do you think you're doing?
ماذا تعتقد أنك تفعل؟
Do you think I'm going to let you get away with this?
هل تعتقد أنني سأسمح لك بالتخلص من هذا؟
There's nothing wrong with me!
لا يوجد شيء خاطئ معي!
I said I'm perfectly fine!
قلت أنني بخير تماما!
You think I have dementia, don't you?
هل تعتقد أنني مصاب بالخرف؟
I was faking it on purpose to see how you'd react. Understand?
كنتُ أتظاهر عمدًا لأرى رد فعلك. هل فهمت؟
- I knew you'd be this disrespectful! - What matters is,
- كنت أعلم أنك ستكون بهذه الوقاحة! - المهم هو،
there's no one here on your side, Father.
لا يوجد أحد هنا بجانبك يا أبي.
And I don't care whether you have dementia or not,
ولا يهمني إذا كنت تعاني من الخرف أم لا،
- and I won't be changing my mind. - What?
- ولن أغير رأيي. - ماذا؟
So you're really going to throw me in a nursing home?
إذن أنت حقا سوف ترميني في دار رعاية المسنين؟
Well, you should have treated me better then.
حسنًا، كان ينبغي عليك أن تعاملني بشكل أفضل حينها.
What have I ever denied you?
ماذا أنكرتك عليه؟
What did I ever do to you?
ماذا فعلت لك؟
You can think about that in the nursing home.
يمكنك التفكير في ذلك في دار التمريض.
Get him out of here. Now.
أخرجوه من هنا الآن.
Let go of me!
أتركني!
You little brat!
يا لك من طفل صغير!
You brat, I'll...
أيها الوغد، سأ...
What did you find out?
ماذا وجدت؟
Tae Joo looked into it. The columbarium is safe.
نظر تاي جو إليه. الكولومباريوم آمن.
There was no fire.
لم يكن هناك حريق.
Really?
حقًا؟
So that means someone deliberately fed me false information.
وهذا يعني أن شخصًا ما قام عمدًا بإعطائي معلومات كاذبة.
Who do you think?
من تعتقد؟
Someone who knows you best.
شخص يعرفك بشكل أفضل.
Someone who knows what it takes to make you act.
شخص يعرف ما يلزم لجعلك تتصرف.
It's Kim Sun Jae.
إنه كيم سون جاي.
Something must be going down at Chairman Min's house right now.
يبدو أن هناك شيئًا ما يحدث في منزل الرئيس مين الآن.
Looks like Min Kyung Chae and Kim Sun Jae decided today was the day.
يبدو أن مين كيونغ تشاي وكيم سون جاي قررا أن اليوم هو اليوم.
Tae Kyung is on his way there too, so you'd better hurry.
تاي كيونغ في طريقه إلى هناك أيضًا، لذا من الأفضل أن تسرع.
Got it.
فهمتها.
Let go of me.
أتركني.
You punks! Do you have any idea who I am?
أيها الأوغاد! هل لديكم أي فكرة عن من أنا؟
I said, let go!
قلت دعه يذهب!
Let him go.
دعوه يذهب.
Who ordered you to do this?
من أمرك بفعل هذا؟
What are you doing here, Director Moon?
ماذا تفعل هنا يا مدير مون؟
How did you know to come here?
كيف عرفت أنك أتيت إلى هنا؟
Does that matter right now?
هل هذا يهم الآن؟
This illegal act that's taking place.
هذا العمل غير القانوني الذي يحدث.
Did you order this?
هل طلبت هذا؟
I'm asking you. Did you order this?
أسألك، هل طلبت هذا؟
Who do you think you're shouting at? So what if she ordered it?
من تظن أنك تصرخ عليه؟ ماذا لو أمرت بذلك؟
How can you say that to this crime in broad daylight?
كيف يمكنك أن تقول ذلك عن هذه الجريمة في وضح النهار؟
As a lawyer, you of all people should know.
باعتبارك محاميًا، يجب عليك أنت من بين جميع الأشخاص أن تعرف ذلك.
This is a felony. It's called kidnapping.
هذه جريمة جنائية، تُسمى اختطافًا.
Stay out of this. The Chairman has dementia,
ابتعد عن هذا. الرئيس مصاب بالخرف.
and we're just trying to get him into a specialized facility.
ونحن نحاول فقط نقله إلى منشأة متخصصة.
Dementia? Who? I keep telling you I'm fine!
الخرف؟ من؟ أقول لك دائمًا أنني بخير!
That's what dementia patients always say. That there's nothing wrong with them.
هذا ما يقوله مرضى الخرف دائمًا: لا بأس بهم.
You bastard!
أيها الوغد!
You need his wife's permission since she's his legal guardian.
تحتاج إلى إذن زوجته لأنها الوصية القانونية عليه.
I am his daughter.
انا ابنته
Even so, you need his wife's permission first.
ومع ذلك، فأنت بحاجة إلى إذن زوجته أولاً.
Seriously, what is your problem?
بجدية، ما هي مشكلتك؟
So I'm supposed to just leave a man with dementia at home?
فهل من المفترض أن أترك رجلاً مصابًا بالخرف في المنزل؟
He was all by himself in an empty house today.
لقد كان بمفرده في منزل فارغ اليوم.
If something happens to him, are you going to take responsibility?
إذا حدث له شيء هل ستتحمل المسؤولية؟
You didn't engineer this by making sure he was home alone, did you?
لم تقم بتدبير هذا الأمر من خلال التأكد من أنه كان بمفرده في المنزل، أليس كذلك؟
An involuntary commitment like this...
التزام لا إرادي مثل هذا...
I'm about to call the police. Let's see how this plays out.
سأتصل بالشرطة. لنرَ كيف ستسير الأمور.
I said I'm giving my consent! As his daughter!
قلتُ إني أوافق! كابنته!
We even have his doctor's report. Who are you to butt in?
حتى أن لدينا تقرير طبيبه. من أنت لتتدخل في هذا الأمر؟
We'll sort out the legal issues later. Get him in the car before it starts.
سنُحلّ المسائل القانونية لاحقًا. أدخلوه إلى السيارة قبل أن تبدأ.
- We need to get him admitted immediately. - You brat...
- نحن بحاجة إلى إدخاله إلى المستشفى على الفور. - أيها الوغد...
Didn't you hear what I said?
ألم تسمع ما قلته؟
- I said get him in the car now! - You brat!
- قلت أدخله إلى السيارة الآن! - أيها الوغد!
- Where are you going! - Let him go!
- إلى أين أنت ذاهب! - دعه يذهب!
- Get out of the way! - Move, I said!
- ابتعد عن الطريق! - تحرك، قلت!
- You punks! - Let go! I said, let go!
- أيها الأوغاد! - دعهم يذهبوا! قلت، دعهم يذهبوا!
- You bastards! - I said, take your hands off him!
- قلت، ارفع يديك عنه!
- Let go, you scum! - Move!
-اتركهم أيها الحثالة! -تحرك!
- You won't let go? - No, you can't!
-لن تتركني؟ -لا، لا يمكنك!
Take your hands off him!
ارفع يديك عنه!
Who do you think you're taking without my permission as his guardian?
من تعتقد أنك تأخذه دون إذني كوصي عليه؟
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
هل لديك أي فكرة عما تفعله؟
Do you want to find out what happens if you don't stop right now?
هل تريد أن تعرف ماذا سيحدث إذا لم تتوقف الآن؟
I'll have every single one of you in court.
سأحضر كل واحد منكم إلى المحكمة.
Kidnapping a dementia patient, blackmail, violence, and confinement...
اختطاف مريض الخرف، ابتزاز، عنف، واحتجاز...
I'll charge you with everything I can.
سأحاسبك بكل ما أستطيع.
And I'll make sure you get the maximum sentence.
وسوف أتأكد من حصولك على أقصى عقوبة.
Mark my words.
تذكر كلامي.
You think I'm bluffing?
هل تعتقد أنني أخادع؟
You call yourself his daughter after this?
هل تسمي نفسك ابنته بعد هذا؟
Where are you trying to send your sick father?
أين تحاول إرسال والدك المريض؟
You're going to lock him up until he dies?
هل ستحبسه حتى يموت؟
Says who?
يقول من؟
As of today, you're no daughter of his, not even human.
اعتبارًا من اليوم، أنت لست ابنته، ولا حتى إنسانة.
What you did today?
ماذا فعلت اليوم؟
The Chairman might forgive you, but I never will.
قد يسامحك الرئيس، لكنني لن أفعل ذلك أبدًا.
Chairman, let's go inside.
السيد الرئيس، دعنا ندخل إلى الداخل.
This way.
من هنا.
You must have been so scared.
لا بد أنك كنت خائفًا جدًا.
Would you like something to calm your nerves?
هل تريد شيئا لتهدئة أعصابك؟
I can't believe your daughter did this. How could she betray you like that?
لا أصدق أن ابنتك فعلت هذا. كيف تخونك هكذا؟
Of all people.
من كل الناس.
Chairman, maybe it's a blessing you can't comprehend all this.
السيد الرئيس، ربما يكون من حسن الحظ أنك لا تستطيع استيعاب كل هذا.
To be betrayed like this by the child you trusted most.
أن يتم خيانتك بهذه الطريقة من قبل الطفل الذي كنت تثق به أكثر من غيره.
How could you possibly endure it if you were in your right mind?
كيف يمكنك أن تتحمل ذلك لو كنت في عقلك الصحيح؟
I just stepped out for a minute on an urgent matter...
لقد خرجت للتو لمدة دقيقة بشأن مسألة عاجلة ...
and who could have known all this would happen?
ومن كان ليعلم أن كل هذا سيحدث؟
It's all my fault.
إنه خطئي كله.
It's not your fault.
إنه ليس خطؤك.
Stop crying.
توقف عن البكاء.
Chairman?
رئيس؟
I don't have dementia. I'm perfectly lucid.
أنا لا أعاني من الخرف. أنا في كامل وعيي.
I was faking it for a reason.
لقد كنت أتظاهر بذلك لسبب ما.
Are you serious? Are you really okay?
هل أنت جاد؟ هل أنت بخير حقًا؟
- So you're really lucid? - Yes, I told you I am.
- إذن أنت واعي حقًا؟ - نعم، لقد أخبرتك أنني كذلك.
Then what could possibly be the reason? I really thought you had dementia.
إذن ما السبب المحتمل؟ ظننتُ حقًا أنك مصاب بالخرف.
You scared me half to death!
لقد أفزعتني حتى الموت!
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
If I'd known you'd worry this much, I wouldn't have done it.
لو كنت أعلم أنك ستقلق بهذا القدر، لم أكن لأفعل ذلك.
That's enough now.
هذا يكفي الآن.
You're just making me feel more guilty.
أنت فقط تجعلني أشعر بالذنب أكثر.
I didn't think things would get this out of hand.
لم أكن أعتقد أن الأمور سوف تخرج عن السيطرة.
Why aren't you answering me?
لماذا لا تجيبني؟
I asked you how you got here.
سألتك كيف وصلت إلى هنا.
Did Lucia call you or something?
هل اتصلت بك لوسيا أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
That's what I'd like to know.
هذا ما أود أن أعرفه.
It seems the two of you are still secretly in touch.
يبدو أنكما لا تزالان على اتصال سراً.
There's a name for that. It's called an affair.
هناك اسم لذلك، يُسمى علاقة غرامية.
I came to see the Chairman about a separate matter.
لقد جئت لرؤية الرئيس بشأن مسألة منفصلة.
What business could you possibly have with a man who's lost his mind?
ما العمل الذي يمكن أن يكون لك مع رجل فقد عقله؟
There's no need to listen to him.
ليست هناك حاجة للاستماع إليه.
You think I don't know you're in touch, cooking up some scheme?
هل تعتقد أنني لا أعرف أنك على اتصال بي، أو تخطط لمخطط ما؟
I was going to keep my mouth shut, but you're forcing my hand.
كنت سأبقي فمي مغلقًا، لكنك تجبرني على ذلك.
You asked why I'm here, right?
لقد سألتني لماذا أنا هنا، أليس كذلك؟
I came to brief the Chairman on the secret ledger.
لقد جئت لإطلاع الرئيس على السجل السري.
Secret ledger?
دفتر سري؟
- And what's that supposed to be? - What is he talking about?
- وماذا يفترض أن يكون هذا؟ - ماذا يتحدث عنه؟
Leave. Now.
إرحل الآن.
We don't need you getting involved in this.
نحن لا نحتاج إلى تدخلك في هذا الأمر.
Didn't you hear me? I said get out of here!
ألم تسمعني؟ قلت اخرج من هنا!
All right, if you say so.
حسنًا، إذا قلت ذلك.
I can always see the Chairman another time.
أستطيع دائمًا رؤية الرئيس في وقت آخر.
What was that about a secret ledger?
ماذا كان هذا عن دفتر الحسابات السري؟
I have no idea.
ليس لدي أي فكرة.
He's just talking nonsense.
إنه يتكلم فقط بالهراء.
Don't pay him any mind.
لا تعير له أي اهتمام.
Right now, what's more important is what we're going to do about the Chairman.
والآن، الأمر الأكثر أهمية هو ما سنفعله بشأن الرئيس.
Let's go to the company first. No, wait, let's stop by the hospital.
لنذهب إلى الشركة أولًا. لا، انتظر، لنتوقف عند المستشفى.
There's something I need to confirm with Dr. Kim.
هناك شيء أريد تأكيده مع الدكتور كيم.
My father is claiming he doesn't have dementia.
يزعم والدي أنه لا يعاني من الخرف.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
He seemed a little off to me.
لقد بدا لي غريبا بعض الشيء.
It was like he was lucid for a moment.
لقد كان وكأنه في وعيه للحظة.
You were right.
لقد كنت على حق.
The Chairman doesn't have dementia.
الرئيس لا يعاني من الخرف.
What did you just say?
ماذا قلت للتو؟
Then why in the world?
ثم لماذا في العالم؟
What was that report you gave me?
ما هو التقرير الذي أعطيتني إياه؟
That was on the Chairman's orders.
وكان ذلك بناء على أوامر الرئيس.
He asked to be diagnosed...
وطلب تشخيص حالته...
with dementia,
مع الخرف،
so I simply obliged.
لذلك قمت ببساطة بالامتثال.
And you just played along because the Chairman asked you to?
وهل لعبت فقط لأن الرئيس طلب منك ذلك؟
And you call yourself a doctor? How could you be so thoughtless?
وتسمي نفسك طبيبًا؟ كيف تكون طائشًا إلى هذه الدرجة؟
Didn't you stop to think about how worried his children would be?
ألم تتوقفي لتفكري في مدى القلق الذي قد يشعر به أطفاله؟
Funny you should say that.
من المضحك أن تقول ذلك.
I wasn't sure...
لم أكن متأكدا...
how worried his kids would be.
كم سيكون أطفاله قلقين.
And I'm sure the Chairman felt the same.
وأنا متأكد من أن الرئيس شعر بنفس الشيء.
That's why he pulled a stunt like this.
لهذا السبب قام بهذه الحيلة.
I'm not letting this go.
لن أترك هذا الأمر.
I'm filing a lawsuit. You're not getting away with this!
سأرفع دعوى قضائية. لن تنجو من هذا!
Instead of taking your anger out on me,
بدلا من أن تصب غضبك علي،
you should reflect on why you've gotten...
ينبغي عليك أن تفكر في سبب حصولك على...
on your father's bad side.
على الجانب السيئ لوالدك.
Please, calm down.
من فضلك، اهدأ.
That conniving old man.
هذا الرجل العجوز المتواطئ.
Does he have nothing better to do than test his own kids?
هل ليس لديه ما هو أفضل ليفعله سوى اختبار أطفاله؟
He completely played me, didn't he?
لقد لعب معي بشكل كامل، أليس كذلك؟
I fell for the Chairman's act,
لقد وقعت في فخ الرئيس،
didn't I?
ألم أفعل؟
(Mingang Distribution)
(توزيع)
Please calm down. At this point, what's done is done.
من فضلك اهدأ. في هذه المرحلة، انتهى ما حدث.
How can I possibly calm down? I completely showed him my hand.
كيف لي أن أهدأ؟ لقد أظهرت له يدي بكل وضوح.
I'm in the same boat.
أنا في نفس القارب.
I feel completely exposed in front of him right now.
أشعر أنني مكشوفة تمامًا أمامه الآن.
I can't forgive him for orchestrating this whole thing on purpose.
لا أستطيع أن أسامحه على تدبير هذا الأمر عمدًا.
What on earth was he trying to test? Who was he trying to sound out?
ما الذي كان يحاول اختباره؟ من كان يحاول استقصاءه؟
Where have you been?
أين كنت؟
The holiday home in Yangpyeong.
بيت العطلة في يانغبيونغ.
I didn't want to go, but Manager Gong insisted.
لم أكن أرغب في الذهاب، لكن المدير غونغ أصر.
The fact that you dragged her there when she didn't want to go...
حقيقة أنك سحبتها إلى هناك عندما لم ترغب في الذهاب...
means you must have had a reason.
يعني أنه لابد أن يكون لديك سبب.
Then again, it's not like you can say no to Kyung Chae.
ومرة أخرى، ليس من الممكن أن تقول لا لكيونج تشاي.
You were home?
كنت في المنزل؟
No. I was out and just got back myself.
لا، لقد كنت بالخارج ثم عدت بنفسي.
And where have you two been?
وأين كنتما؟
We got some free concert tickets.
لقد حصلنا على بعض تذاكر الحفل المجانية.
We already had dinner, so don't worry about us.
لقد تناولنا العشاء بالفعل، فلا تقلق علينا.
- Okay. - Must have been a nice place.
- حسنًا. - لا بد أن يكون مكانًا لطيفًا.
A globally acclaimed restaurant.
مطعم مشهور عالميًا.
Someone pulled strings and got us a table at a place that's impossible to get into.
لقد تمكن شخص ما من الحصول لنا على طاولة في مكان من المستحيل الدخول إليه.
Don't tell me Kim Sun Jae arranged that concert and restaurant?
لا تخبرني أن كيم سون جاي هو من رتب هذا الحفل والمطعم؟
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
They're just unbelievable.
إنهم لا يصدقون.
They all know you're sick in bed, yet they're all out and about.
إنهم جميعًا يعرفون أنك مريض في السرير، ومع ذلك فهم جميعًا بالخارج.
What can you expect from a bunch like that?
ماذا يمكنك أن تتوقع من مجموعة مثل هذه؟
It's not like I'm really sick, so don't be upset.
ليس الأمر وكأنني مريض حقًا، لذلك لا تنزعج.
But why would you do something like that?
ولكن لماذا تريد أن تفعل شيئا كهذا؟
To say it was dementia, of all things.
لأقول أنها كانت الخرف، من بين كل الأشياء.
You have no idea how scared I was.
ليس لديك فكرة عن مدى خوفي.
Why? Were you afraid I'd be a burden on you for life?
لماذا؟ هل كنت خائفًا من أن أكون عبئًا عليك طوال حياتك؟
No.
لا.
I was afraid I was going to lose you.
كنت خائفة من أن أفقدك.
I don't care if you're a burden. I just want you to stay with me always.
لا يهمني إن كنتَ عبئًا، كل ما أريده هو أن تبقى معي دائمًا.
I was afraid that might not happen.
كنت خائفة من أن هذا قد لا يحدث.
I had no idea.
لم يكن لدي أي فكرة.
There's something I have to confess to you.
هناك شيء يجب أن أعترف لك به.
Do you know why I staged this whole thing?
هل تعلم لماذا قمت بهذا الشيء كله؟
I was afraid I'd end up like Chairman Mo of Inam Construction.
كنت خائفًا من أن أصبح مثل رئيس مجلس إدارة شركة إينام للإنشاءات.
If dementia suddenly made me unable to even control my own bowels,
إذا كان الخرف فجأة جعلني غير قادر حتى على التحكم في أمعائي،
would you believe I had to act pretend I had dementia...
هل تصدق أنني اضطررت إلى التظاهر بأنني مصاب بالخرف؟
because of my greedy kids who'd jump at the chance to take over?
بسبب أطفالي الجشعين الذين ينتهزون الفرصة للاستيلاء على السلطة؟
I'm telling you, even a man like me got scared.
أنا أقول لك، حتى رجل مثلي أصبح خائفا.
Of course, it's not like I trusted you, either.
بالطبع، ليس الأمر وكأنني وثقت بك أيضًا.
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
I knew I'd failed as a father, but I had no idea it was this bad.
لقد عرفت أنني فشلت كأب، لكن لم يكن لدي أي فكرة أن الأمر كان سيئًا إلى هذا الحد.
I used to worry they'd tear each other apart,
كنت أشعر بالقلق من أنهم سوف يمزقون بعضهم البعض،
but who knew they'd try to come after me, too?
لكن من كان يعلم أنهم سيحاولون مهاجمتي أيضًا؟
You should have at least told me.
كان ينبغي عليك أن تخبرني على الأقل.
What can I say? It's just the way I am.
ماذا أستطيع أن أقول؟ هكذا أنا.
But not anymore.
ولكن ليس بعد الآن.
Now that I've seen how loyal you truly are,
الآن بعد أن رأيت مدى ولائك الحقيقي،
from now on, if you say the sky is square, it's square to me.
من الآن فصاعدا، إذا قلت أن السماء مربعة، فهي مربعة بالنسبة لي.
If you say it,
إذا قلت ذلك،
I'd believe that black is white.
أعتقد أن الأسود هو الأبيض.
Everything was quiet today, right?
كان كل شيء هادئًا اليوم، أليس كذلك؟
Yes, it was.
نعم كان كذلك.
Hey, where've you been on your day off?
مرحبًا، أين كنت في يوم إجازتك؟
I had plans to meet up with someone.
لقد كان لدي خطط للقاء شخص ما.
Manager Gong, why did you and Se Ri...
المدير غونغ، لماذا فعلت أنت وسي ري...
suddenly go to the villa in Yangpyeong?
فجأة اذهب إلى الفيلا في يانغبيونغ؟
Oh, we just wanted to get some fresh air.
أوه، أردنا فقط الحصول على بعض الهواء النقي.
Wait a minute!
انتظر دقيقة!
Then that means no one was home?
إذن هذا يعني أنه لم يكن هناك أحد في المنزل؟
What about her?
ماذا عنها؟
Is she home?
هل هي في المنزل؟
I think she just got back from going out, too.
أعتقد أنها عادت للتو من الخروج أيضًا.
What did you just say?
ماذا قلت للتو؟
What is going on?
ما الذي يجري؟
You left the house unattended, didn't you?
لقد تركت المنزل دون مراقبة، أليس كذلك؟
- Wait a second. - Are you out of your mind?
- انتظر ثانية. - هل أنت خارج عقلك؟
After I specifically warned you!
بعد أن حذرتك بشكل خاص!
And my father?
وأبي؟
Oh, I thought...
أوه، اعتقدت...
Kyung Chae had driven everyone out and done something to Dad in the meantime.
كان كيونج تشاي قد طرد الجميع وقام بشيء ما لأبي في هذه الأثناء.
My sister is just itching to throw you in a nursing home, you know?
أختي تريد فقط أن ترميك في دار رعاية المسنين، هل تعلم؟
Believe me, I'd love to do the same thing,
صدقني، أود أن أفعل الشيء نفسه،
but then that fox would steal the company, so I'm holding myself back.
لكن بعد ذلك سوف يسرق هذا الثعلب الشركة، لذا فأنا أكبح نفسي.
You probably can't understand me, but I have plenty of gripes with you too!
ربما لا يمكنك فهمي، ولكن لدي الكثير من الشكاوى منك أيضًا!
If you've got such a grudge,
إذا كان لديك مثل هذا الحقد،
why don't you two just send me to a home?
لماذا لا ترسلوني إلى منزل؟
You all thought you had it made when I got dementia, didn't you?
لقد ظننتم جميعًا أنكم وصلتم إلى القمة عندما أصبت بالخرف، أليس كذلك؟
You were all practically giddy.
لقد كنتم جميعا في غاية السعادة.
You saw your chance and had no problem saying what was really on your minds.
لقد رأيت فرصتك ولم تجد أي مشكلة في قول ما كان يدور في ذهنك حقًا.
Thanks to this, I know for sure what you all really think of me.
بفضل هذا، أعرف بالتأكيد ما تفكرون به حقًا عني.
Every last one of you is a rotten piece of filth.
كل واحد منكم هو قطعة قذرة متعفنة.
You're nothing but vipers disguised as my children.
أنتم لستم سوى أفاعي متنكرة في صورة أطفالي.
You used my money and bled me dry, then tried to discard me...
لقد استخدمت أموالي وأستنزفتني حتى أصبحت سفلى، ثم حاولت التخلص مني...
when you thought I was useless.
عندما كنت تعتقد أنني عديم الفائدة.
You filthy mongrels.
أيها الوغد القذر.
This can't be happening!
هذا لا يمكن أن يحدث!
Father, you don't have dementia?
أبي، هل أنت لا تعاني من الخرف؟
What? Are you disappointed your old man is perfectly fine?
ماذا؟ هل تشعر بخيبة أمل لأن والدك بخير تمامًا؟
Are you disappointed I'm not a senile man who can't even control his own bladder?
هل أنت محبط لأنني لست رجلاً خرفًا لا يستطيع حتى التحكم في مثانته؟
What's gotten into him? I thought he had dementia.
ماذا حدث له؟ ظننت أنه مصاب بالخرف.
- He says he doesn't. - Well, that's a relief, I guess...
- يقول أنه لا يفعل ذلك. - حسنًا، هذا أمر مريح، على ما أعتقد...
Just think about it for a second! Think!
فكر في الأمر لثانية واحدة فقط! فكر!
Then again, I guess you can't think.
ومرة أخرى، أعتقد أنك لا تستطيع التفكير.
Anyway, with you ending up like this, I'd say you got off easy.
على أية حال، مع انتهائك بهذا الشكل، أود أن أقول أنك نجحت بسهولة.
You should have been a better person. And maybe taken care of me.
كان ينبغي أن تكون شخصًا أفضل. وربما كنتَ تهتم بي.
What am I going to do now?
ماذا سأفعل الآن؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
Did you say something you shouldn't have to Father?
هل قلت شيئا لا ينبغي لك أن تقوله لأبي؟
You got flustered and said something awful to him, didn't you?
لقد شعرت بالارتباك وقلت له شيئًا فظيعًا، أليس كذلك؟
See? You should've been more careful, like me.
أرأيت؟ كان عليك أن تكون أكثر حذرًا، مثلي.
Seriously...
بجد...
Oh, my God! What am I going to do?
يا إلهي! ماذا سأفعل؟
That's exactly what I can't forgive you for.
هذا بالضبط ما لا أستطيع أن أسامحك عليه.
That you're a calculating man who would even exploit his own child.
أنك رجل حاسب لدرجة أنك تستغل حتى طفله.
I know you were blinded by her, but still!
أعرف أنك كنت أعمى منها، ولكن لا يزال!
I, Manager Gong...
أنا المدير غونغ...
I mean, is this what I, Gong Mae Ja,
أعني، هل هذا ما أنا، غونغ ماي جا،
get after all these years I've served this family?
ماذا بعد كل هذه السنوات التي خدمت فيها هذه العائلة؟
Chairman.
رئيس مجلس الإدارة.
You'll be punished for acting this way.
سيتم معاقبتك على التصرف بهذه الطريقة.
I must've been out of my mind.
يبدو أنني كنت خارج عقلي.
Why can't I keep my big mouth shut?
لماذا لا أستطيع إبقاء فمي الكبير مغلقا؟
What am I going to do?
ماذا سأفعل؟
There's no way...
لا يوجد طريقة...
the Chairman will let this slide. What should we do?
سيتجاهل الرئيس هذا الأمر. ماذا علينا أن نفعل؟
I wouldn't let it slide either if I were him.
لن أسمح لهذا الأمر بالانزلاق حتى لو كنت مكانه.
Now he knows what his kids really think of him.
الآن يعرف ما يفكر به أطفاله حقًا عنه.
You know how he is.
أنت تعرف كيف هو.
I can't believe things ended up like this.
لا أستطيع أن أصدق أن الأمور انتهت بهذا الشكل.
This is all Lucia's fault.
كل هذا خطأ لوسيا.
If only Lucia hadn't gotten in the way.
لو لم تكن لوسيا عائقًا.
For now, let's see the Chairman's reaction.
والآن دعونا نرى رد فعل الرئيس.
And as for the two of us,
وأما نحن الاثنين،
we should probably lay low for a while.
ربما ينبغي لنا أن نبقى بعيدين عن الأنظار لفترة من الوقت.
Sir. I'm here.
سيدي، أنا هنا.
- Welcome. - Come on in.
- أهلا بك. - تفضل بالدخول.
He tells me you're working at our in-laws' company?
يخبرني أنك تعمل في شركة أصهارنا؟
- I'm sorry, I should've told you sooner. - What's to be sorry about?
- أنا آسف، كان يجب أن أخبرك في وقت سابق. - ما الذي يجعلك آسفًا؟
That makes sense. A handsome, accomplished man like you...
هذا منطقي. رجل وسيم ومتميز مثلك...
belongs at a major company.
ينتمي إلى شركة كبيرة.
Hang on a second. I'll go get you some tea.
انتظر لحظة، سأحضر لك بعض الشاي.
At work, do you hear any news about Chairman Min?
في العمل هل تسمع أي أخبار عن الرئيس مين؟
I know it's bad news, so I hate to ask, but this uncertainty is killing me.
أعرف أنها أخبار سيئة، لذا أكره أن أسأل، لكن هذا الشك يقتلني.
I don't think you need to worry too much.
لا أعتقد أنك بحاجة للقلق كثيرًا.
He'll be back to his old self again before you know it.
سوف يعود إلى حالته القديمة مرة أخرى قبل أن تعرف ذلك.
What kind of crazy talk is that?
ما هذا الكلام المجنون؟
How does someone with dementia just get better?
كيف يمكن لشخص مصاب بالخرف أن يتحسن؟
Because I don't think he actually has dementia.
لأنني لا أعتقد أنه يعاني من الخرف فعليا.
- It's just a hunch. - What are you talking about?
- إنه مجرد حدس. - عما تتحدث؟
I'll go to Mingang Distribution myself. I might even get to see Lucia there.
سأذهب إلى مينغانغ للتوزيع بنفسي. ربما أتمكن من رؤية لوسيا هناك.
I've been wondering how she's doing anyway.
لقد كنت أتساءل كيف حالها على أية حال.
You should. And Lucia was asking for you, by the way.
يجب عليك ذلك. ولوسيا كانت تسأل عنك، بالمناسبة.
What? Lucia asked about me?
ماذا؟ سألت لوسيا عني؟
When? Where? How? What was her tone? Longing? Desperate?
متى؟ أين؟ كيف؟ كيف كانت نبرتها؟ شوق؟ يأس؟
How am I supposed to interpret that? Come on, give me some advice!
كيف أفسر ذلك؟ هيا، أعطني بعض النصائح!
What am I going to do?
ماذا سأفعل؟
Okay, I understand. How is this your fault?
حسناً، فهمت. كيف يكون هذا خطأك؟
You were just following my orders.
لقد كنت فقط تتبع أوامري.
I'll call you later.
سأتصل بك لاحقا.
- Was that Dr. Kim? - Yes. He said Kyung Chae visited him.
- هل كان ذلك الدكتور كيم؟ - نعم. قال إن كيونغ تشاي زارته.
So she knows everything now?
فهل هي تعرف كل شيء الآن؟
Looks that way.
يبدو بهذه الطريقة.
I can't let you go in alone. I'm just too worried.
لا أستطيع أن أدعك تدخل وحدك. أنا قلق جدًا.
Who knows what Kyung Chae will do there? I'm going back to work.
من يعلم ماذا ستفعل كيونغ تشاي هناك؟ سأعود للعمل.
I don't care about the title. As long as I can be by your side.
لا يهمني اللقب، ما دمت بجانبك.
I need to see for myself that you're safe. I can't stay home worrying. It's torture.
أريد أن أتأكد بنفسي من سلامتك. لا أستطيع البقاء في المنزل قلقًا. إنه عذاب.
Are you that worried about me?
هل أنت قلق علي لهذه الدرجة؟
Do you even need to ask?
هل تحتاج حتى إلى السؤال؟
Then go back to work if you want. But don't do it just for me.
ثم عد إلى العمل إن أردت. لكن لا تفعل ذلك من أجلي فقط.
- Only come back when you're ready to. - But I do want to work again.
- لا تعود إلا عندما تكون مستعدًا لذلك. - لكنني أريد أن أعمل مرة أخرى.
Start immediately. What's stopping you? Mingang is my company.
ابدأ فورًا. ما الذي يمنعك؟ مينغانغ هي شركتي.
That's a call I'm allowed to make.
هذا هو القرار الذي يُسمح لي بإجرائه.
Dad!
أب!
Dad, are you all right now?
أبي هل أنت بخير الآن؟
Can't you see for yourself? I'm fine, so stop worrying.
ألا ترى بنفسك؟ أنا بخير، فلا تقلق.
Where is everyone? Why aren't they here?
أين الجميع؟ لماذا ليسوا هنا؟
I said get out of here!
قلت اخرج من هنا!
Come on. I'm serious, he's going to kill me!
هيا، أنا جاد، سوف يقتلني!
Then go out there and face him! Hurry! What other choice is there?
إذًا، اخرج وواجهه! أسرع! ما من خيار آخر؟
No, I can't...
لا لا استطيع...
What are you all doing, hiding like rats in a hole?
ماذا تفعلون جميعًا، تختبئون مثل الفئران في الحفرة؟
Did you commit a crime or something?
هل ارتكبت جريمة أو شيء من هذا القبيل؟
Please, don't be like this.
من فضلك لا تكن هكذا.
They probably didn't get a wink of sleep last night.
ربما لم يحصلوا على غمضة عين من النوم الليلة الماضية.
Please, just this once, let it go for my sake.
من فضلك، هذه المرة فقط، دع الأمر من أجلي.
I'm only going this easy on you because of your stepmother.
أنا فقط أذهب بهذه السهولة معك بسبب زوجة أبيك.
You should be on your knees thanking her.
ينبغي عليك أن تكون على ركبتيك تشكره.
- And Kyung Chae? - She didn't come home last night.
- وكيونغ تشاي؟ - لم تعد إلى المنزل الليلة الماضية.
After what she pulled on her own father,
بعد ما فعلته بأبيها،
if she could come back and sleep well, she wouldn't be human.
لو استطاعت أن تعود وتنام جيدًا، فلن تكون إنسانة.
Calm down and let's get you to work.
اهدأ وسنذهب إلى العمل.
(Mingang Distribution)
(توزيع)
You're in early.
لقد وصلت مبكرا.
Are you feeling all right, sir?
هل تشعر أنك بخير يا سيدي؟
Come have a cup of tea in my office.
تعالوا لتناول كوب من الشاي في مكتبي.
What was that about at my house yesterday?
ماذا كان يحدث في منزلي أمس؟
Vice Director Min told me your condition and came because I was concerned.
نائب المدير مين أخبرني بحالتك وجاء لأنني كنت قلقًا.
Of course, I was hesitant to interfere in a private family matter.
وبطبيعة الحال، كنت مترددة في التدخل في مسألة عائلية خاصة.
In any case, I apologize.
على أية حال، أنا أعتذر.
There's nothing to apologize for.
ليس هناك ما نعتذر عنه.
I'm embarrassed you had to see that side of my family,
أنا أشعر بالحرج لأنك اضطررت إلى رؤية هذا الجانب من عائلتي،
but now I know you're on my side, and that's what matters.
ولكن الآن أعلم أنك في صفي، وهذا هو ما يهم.
I'm not sure I understand what you mean, sir.
أنا لست متأكدًا من أنني أفهم ما تقصده، سيدي.
I think I may have misjudged you.
أعتقد أنني ربما أخطأت في الحكم عليك.
I thought you must resent me.
اعتقدت أنك يجب أن تستاء مني.
But I never expected you to come to my aid.
ولكنني لم أتوقع أبدًا أن تأتي لمساعدتي.
I would have rushed to help anyone in the same situation.
كنت سأسارع إلى مساعدة أي شخص في نفس الوضع.
It's not because you're the Chairman.
ليس لأنك الرئيس.
I'd do it even for my worst enemy.
سأفعل ذلك حتى بالنسبة لأسوأ أعدائي.
Is that another lesson from your father?
هل هذا درس آخر من والدك؟
Yes, it is.
نعم إنه كذلك.
It sounds like I owe my life to your father, then.
يبدو الأمر وكأنني أدين بحياتي لوالدك، إذن.
And you're the one who did the unspeakable to a father like that.
وأنت من فعلت ذلك لأب لا يمكن وصفه.
Hey, Moon Tae Kyung.
مرحبًا مون تاي كيونغ.
If you mention the secret ledger to anyone,
إذا ذكرت السجل السري لأي شخص،
you and Lucia are finished. Got it?
انتهيتَ أنتَ ولوسيا. فهمتَ؟
You think I'll go down alone?
هل تعتقد أنني سأذهب وحدي؟
No. Even if I go to hell,
لا. حتى لو ذهبت إلى الجحيم،
I'm dragging you with me. I refuse to go alone.
أنا أسحبك معي. أرفض الذهاب وحدي.
At least he knows he's going to hell.
على الأقل هو يعلم أنه ذاهب إلى الجحيم.
You nearly gave me a heart attack!
لقد كاد أن يصيبني بنوبة قلبية!
You startled me.
لقد فاجأتني.
If the proposal that is due today, submit it to the Chairman's Office now.
إذا كان المقترح مستحقًا اليوم، فقم بتقديمه إلى مكتب الرئيس الآن.
Are you crazy?
هل انت مجنون؟
You want me to walk right into the lion's den?
هل تريدني أن أذهب مباشرة إلى عرين الأسد؟
I don't have a death wish.
ليس لدي رغبة في الموت.
I'm not going near the Chairman's Office, so get that through your head.
أنا لا أذهب إلى مكان قريب من مكتب الرئيس، لذا تأكد من فهم ذلك.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
مهلا، ماذا تعتقد أنك تفعل؟
Unless you want that office as my grave, don't send me in there. Seriously!
إلا إذا كنت تريد هذا المكتب قبرًا لي، فلا ترسلني إليه. جديًا!
I'm not going. I can't go.
انا لا اذهب. لا استطيع الذهاب.
Where did you stay last night?
أين قضيت الليلة الماضية؟
At the company residence.
في مقر إقامة الشركة.
I feel like I walked right into a trap set by the Chairman.
أشعر وكأنني دخلت مباشرة إلى فخ نصبه الرئيس.
I've never felt so powerless.
لم أشعر أبدًا بهذا القدر من العجز.
I'm sure he intended for someone else to get caught in that trap.
أنا متأكد من أنه كان ينوي أن يقع شخص آخر في هذا الفخ.
That trap was definitely not meant for you.
هذا الفخ بالتأكيد لم يكن مخصصا لك.
It doesn't matter who it was for. I'm the one who got caught.
لا يهم من كان السبب، أنا من تم القبض عليه.
Even if the Chairman picks someone else as his successor, I can't say a word.
حتى لو اختار الرئيس شخصًا آخر خلفًا له، فلن أستطيع أن أقول كلمة واحدة.
Because I've given him the perfect excuse.
لأنني أعطيته العذر المثالي.
So, what's your plan now?
إذن ما هي خطتك الآن؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
For now, all I can do is wait for the Chairman's decision.
في الوقت الحالي، كل ما أستطيع فعله هو انتظار قرار الرئيس.
So now Min Kyung Chae just has to wait to face the music.
لذلك الآن يتعين على مين كيونج تشاي أن تنتظر لمواجهة الموسيقى.
Min Kyung Chae and Kim Sun Jae won't be pulling a stunt like this ever again.
لن يقوم مين كيونج تشاي وكيم سون جاي بمثل هذه الخدعة مرة أخرى.
I knew he was a terrible person, but now I see he's worse than an animal.
كنت أعلم أنه كان شخصًا فظيعًا، لكن الآن أرى أنه أسوأ من الحيوان.
How could he lie about a fire at the columbarium...
كيف يمكنه أن يكذب بشأن حريق في كولومباريوم...
where your daughter rests just to pull off his scheme?
أين ابنتك تستريح فقط لتنفيذ مخططه؟
They thought if they got Chairman Min in a nursing home,
لقد اعتقدوا أنه إذا تمكنوا من إدخال الرئيس مين إلى دار رعاية المسنين،
the world would be theirs for the taking.
العالم سيكون ملكًا لهم.
They'd stop at nothing. Not when what they want is so close.
لن يترددوا في فعل أي شيء. ليس عندما يكون ما يريدونه قريبًا جدًا.
Now that they're about to lose it all, I bet they're an absolute wreck.
الآن بعد أن أصبحوا على وشك خسارة كل شيء، فأنا أراهن أنهم حطام مطلق.
Right. When do you think you'll be back at the company?
حسناً. متى تتوقع عودتك إلى الشركة؟
- Soon. - That's great.
- قريبا. - هذا رائع.
I wonder what position Min Doo Sik will offer you.
أتساءل ما هو المنصب الذي سيقدمه لك مين دو سيك.
I hope it's a position where you can tighten the leash on Min Kyung Chae.
آمل أن يكون هذا موقفًا يمكنك من خلاله تشديد القيود على مين كيونج تشاي.
(Chairman Min Doo Sik)
(الرئيس مين دو سيك)
I can't let you go in alone. I'm just too worried.
لا أستطيع أن أدعك تدخل وحدك. أنا قلق جدًا.
Who knows what Kyung Chae will do there?
من يعلم ماذا سيفعل كيونغ تشاي هناك؟
I'm going back to work. I don't care about the title.
سأعود للعمل. لا يهمني اللقب.
As long as I can be by your side.
طالما أستطيع أن أكون بجانبك.
She's so devoted to me.
إنها مخلصة لي جدًا.
I can't just give a person like that some insignificant position.
لا أستطيع أن أعطي شخصًا مثله منصبًا غير مهم.
Tell CEO Min to come to my office.
اطلب من الرئيس التنفيذي مين أن يأتي إلى مكتبي.
- I was wrong, Father. - What exactly were you wrong about?
- لقد كنت مخطئا يا أبي. - ما الذي كنت مخطئا فيه بالضبط؟
That you tried to ship your father with dementia off to a nursing home?
أنك حاولت إرسال والدك الذي يعاني من الخرف إلى دار رعاية المسنين؟
Or that you acted like you owned Mingang Distribution?
أم أنك تصرفت كما لو كنت مالكًا لشركة Mingang Distribution؟
I said, tell me. What did you do wrong?
قلتُ: أخبرني. ما الخطأ الذي ارتكبته؟
I have no excuse.
ليس لدي عذر.
I promise you.
أعدك.
It will never happen again.
لن يحدث هذا مرة أخرى أبدًا.
In return,
وفي المقابل،
I'll dedicate myself to my role as CEO and boost sales.
سأكرس نفسي لدوري كرئيس تنفيذي وسأعمل على تعزيز المبيعات.
I'll make up for my mistakes, Father, by proving my worth as CEO.
سأعوض أخطائي يا أبي من خلال إثبات جدارتي كرئيس تنفيذي.
No, there's no need for that!
لا، ليس هناك حاجة لذلك!
You won't get the chance to make up for anything as CEO.
لن تحصل على فرصة للتعويض عن أي شيء باعتبارك الرئيس التنفيذي.
What does that mean...
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
You're a failure as a daughter, and you're a failure as a CEO.
أنت فاشلة كابنة، وأنت فاشلة كرئيسة تنفيذية.
Resign as CEO.
الاستقالة من منصب الرئيس التنفيذي.
Step down and start over from the bottom. That's your punishment.
انزل وابدأ من الصفر. هذا عقابك.
An entry-level position?
وظيفة مبتدئة؟
You're joking, right?
أنت تمزح، أليس كذلك؟
How could you do this without even discussing it with me?
كيف يمكنك أن تفعل هذا دون حتى مناقشته معي؟
When did you ask about the nursing home? I won't repeat myself!
متى سألت عن دار المسنين؟ ما راح أكرر كلامي!
Even so, this is going too far.
ورغم ذلك، فهذا أمر مبالغ فيه.
Who else could possibly take my place? Did you forget your philosophy, Father?
من غيري يستطيع أن يأخذ مكاني؟ هل نسيتَ فلسفتك يا أبي؟
That the executive team must be members of the Min family.
أن يكون الفريق التنفيذي من أفراد عائلة مين.
You're not seriously considering putting Soo Jung in my position, are you?
أنت لا تفكر جديا في وضع سو جونغ في مكاني، أليس كذلك؟
It can't be Ji Seop.
لا يمكن أن يكون جي سوب.
So who on earth could possibly take my place?
فمن على الأرض يمكن أن يأخذ مكاني؟
Who says there's no one? There is a perfect candidate.
من قال أنه لا يوجد أحد؟ هناك مرشح مثالي.
A perfect candidate? Who?
مرشح مثالي؟ من؟
Don't tell me...
لا تخبرني...
Is it Lucia?
هل هي لوسيا؟
That's right. Lucia!
هذا صحيح. لوسيا!
I'm putting her in your seat.
سأضعها في مقعدك.
(The Woman Who Swallowed The Sun)
(المرأة التي ابتلعت الشمس)
The old man's gone senile. There's no other explanation.
لقد أصبح الرجل العجوز خرفًا. لا يوجد تفسير آخر.
So Father is kicking Kyung Chae out to put that woman in charge?
إذن هل يقوم الأب بطرد كيونغ تشاي من أجل وضع تلك المرأة في السلطة؟
So, what will it be? Will you resign?
إذن ماذا سيكون الأمر؟ هل ستستقيل؟
Handing the CEO to that woman? Does that make any sense?
تسليم منصب الرئيس التنفيذي لتلك المرأة؟ هل هذا منطقي؟
And you call yourselves my children? You live in my house, stuffing your faces,
وتسمون أنفسكم أبنائي؟ تعيشون في بيتي، تحشو وجوهكم،
and live off my company, yet you defy me? I'm done with all of you!
وتعيش على شركتي، ومع ذلك تتحداني؟ لقد انتهيت منكم جميعًا!
Because I'm signing this house over to her.
لأنني أوقع هذا البيت لها.
(Subtitles are provided by KOCOWA.)
(يتم توفير الترجمة بواسطة KOCOWA.)